[Episode 26]
Le Yan.
Master, I've finished.
Excellent brushwork,
but...
It lacks a finishing touch.
Belated Spring.
At night, news of spring arrived.
It got me in the mood.
I secretly expressed my longing for love.
Only spring knew about my love.
This is Belated Spring.
Since Ling Yi passed away,
I've been feeling uneasy.
The winter is long,
and spring is far out of reach.
But that day,
when I put down the dagger in front of you,
I suddenly realized
the dead are gone,
but the living should live for themselves.
Le Yan, you made me live again.
In the future,
I want to live for myself once more.
It's wonderful that you think this way.
The other day, you were deeply sorrowful,
yet you still managed to assist Director Meng
in fighting corruption.
I admire you deeply,
and I also worry about you.
So I painted this spring scene for you.
Le Yan, all of this is because of you.
Only by your side can I be my true self.
A romantic relationship is forbidden
between teachers and students.
It's going to be a tough road.
But if I persevere,
Le Yan,
will you be brave for me, just this once?
I did not understand what love was,
but seeing my parents support
and love each other,
and seeing Zhi Shu risk everything
to find an antidote for Miss Yan,
and seeing you in utter despair,
I finally understood
that love
can make people risk their lives
and feel heart-wrenching pain.
I do not wish to be trapped by conventions,
or bound by old rites.
Previously,
you had a family.
I dared not overstep the bounds.
But today,
I want to boldly say one thing.
I also
have feelings for you.
I've prepared this gift for a long time,
and today, I can finally give it to you.
It is a love lock.
I personally drew the cloud pattern
on this lock.
With my heart as the lock,
and the gentle breeze as the key,
this lock represents my love for you.
I will never do you wrong.
I want to protect you forever.
Will you be brave for me,
just this once?
[Gu Mansion]
Who are you?
How dare you barge into my house!
You have some nerve!
I am certainly not as bold as you.
You kept the Huxiao Gang as your pawns.
And after using them up,
you even cruelly sentenced your own brother
to death.
You're just a masked coward.
How dare you talk nonsense and threaten me!
Every dirty deal between you and Ling Yun Fei
is enough to warrant the extermination
of your entire clan.
Who exactly are you?
How do you know so much?
Who I am is not important.
What is important is that within three days,
you must present the military deployment map
of Qingzhou to me.
After all, you don't want Meng Ting Hui
to get a copy of this ledger, do you?
The military deployment map is confidential.
If I steal the map for you,
when it's exposed, I'll still be doomed.
Do you think you can survive
by just taking no action?
Meng Ting Hui will soon
trace everything back to you.
Doing nothing means death.
If you work with me,
I can show you a way out.
Like what?
Help your prized student Shen Zhi Li
become empress.
When this country changes hands,
you will still be the head of all officials.
If anything unexpected happens,
she will be your best lifeline.
Since we are to cooperate,
we should be honest with each other.
I also need to know your background.
You are back.
You went to see Lord Gu again.
None of your business.
You don't want
to talk to me anymore?
Since you learned what the peach wood means,
you have been avoiding me.
How long will you keep avoiding me?
It's not that we can't talk.
It's that there are some things
you shouldn't say.
Nian, you are still young.
My feelings have nothing to do with age.
That year,
I was the only one left in my entire family.
It was you who used a handkerchief
to bandage my injured hand.
You told me that mastering martial arts
would be the best consolation for him.
It was also you who took me
to get close to your parents and brother,
and to spar with His Majesty and Huang Bo.
You walked with me through the hardest days.
From then on, I swore
I would grow up quickly to protect you.
Nian, you misunderstood.
In my heart, you are my younger brother.
I have never misunderstood.
I know how I feel about you.
Besides, you and I are not blood-related.
Then you call my parents Mother and Father,
and call Zhi Shu brother.
Isn't that a family tie?
But wouldn't that be even better?
If you and I are together someday,
it will save me the trouble
of changing how I address them.
Don't beat around the bush with me.
I am a few years older than you,
so I am your elder sister.
You are still young
and cannot yet discern your true feelings.
When you meet a better woman you like,
you will know the difference
between family love and romantic love.
There is no woman better than you.
Zhi Li,
I've long been clear
about how I feel about you.
What about you, Zhi Li?
Can you discern your feelings for him?
I am clear about my own feelings.
No need for others to comment.
So in your heart,
compared to Lord Gu,
I am already considered an outsider?
I know that confessing my feelings to you
will create distance between us,
but I don't regret it.
I don't care
how long it takes for you to love me.
Even if it takes a lifetime,
I will gladly wait.
Calm down.
Don't act on impulse.
I have placed the peach wood in your room.
I have already made myself very clear.
Don't...
You love to read ancient law books.
Every time you go out,
you always bring many bamboo slips.
I thought it was inconvenient
to search through them,
so I copied the content you frequently check
into this book.
I deliberately wrote in large characters,
so you won't strain your eyes
when reading at night.
You don't need to feel troubled.
I didn't do this to make you love me.
I hope
that you will be with the one you truly love.
Grain and fodder are the lifeblood
of the army.
Due to your negligence,
the army provisions were looted.
- Execute him without pardon!
- General Huo, Mr. Shen.
Have mercy on me, please!
Mr. Shen, it was under Pang Mu's watch
that the 30,000 dan of grain were lost,
but the bandits were well-trained
and came with great force.
- It's not a capital offense.
- Isn't it?
Beijian's cavalry
is less than 100 li away from here.
If they take this chance to attack now,
we might lose Qingzhou
due to a lack of provisions.
Before His Majesty punishes you,
you should all atone for the crime
by killing yourselves.
Take him away.
General Huo.
General Huo!
Mr. Shen!
Mr. Shen.
The urgent matter is to gather grain.
I have sent an urgent report to the court,
but the allocation process is cumbersome.
And we're pressed for time.
The grain gathered
from official granaries in Qingzhou
can only last for seven days.
Tell the soldiers to hold on for seven days.
I will find a way to get 30,000 dan of grain.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, I got a letter from Zhi Shu.
Your Majesty,
I've infiltrated the Blood Moon Society.
Upon investigation,
their leader is called Mr. Shangguan.
He is most likely hiding in the capital.
The remnants of Zhongwan are based
in Qingzhou
and are conspiring with Beijian.
They intend to provoke a border conflict
while we lost our army provisions.
I've planted secret agents,
but the military situation is urgent.
I hope
Your Majesty will make early preparations.
Beijian has long
coveted the iron mines of Qingzhou.
If the remnants of Zhongwan use this as bait,
Beijian might treacherously break the treaty.
If Zhongwan and Beijian join forces,
I fear war will break out on the border.
Go pass down the order.
Have the Ministry of War
allocate grain to Qingzhou,
and have the elite troops of Shazhou
provide covert support.
Tell Zhi Shu to sabotage the cooperation
between Zhongwan and Beijian,
but remind him
that his own safety must be the top priority.
Yes, Your Majesty.
[Yan Residence]
Don't worry, Mr. Chen.
The contract will be delivered
to Qingzhou within three days.
The Bofeng House branch will
follow the 70-30 profit split as we agreed.
Ms. Yan, you're quite straightforward.
We'll await the contract.
Father, it's windy outside.
Why did you come out?
Back then, when you insisted on going
to the capital with Meng Ting Hui,
I was so angry and smashed three tea sets.
But now it seems
you have indeed seen a larger world with her.
Seeing how you negotiate
with chambers of commerce,
even an old merchant like me
has to admire you.
My daughter,
you have grown up.
Father,
you always opposed me appearing in public
and doing business.
This is the first time
you've praised Meng and me.
Since Ding Chong fell from power,
I've seen the number of merchant caravans
in Shazhou increase by 70 percent.
Not only have our businesses improved,
but even poor families
can now afford to eat meat.
You've gradually changed my mind.
Sweetie, don't try.
You are now the head of our family.
You can't just cry like this.
[Yan Residence]
Fu Zhi.
Zhi Shu.
Master Yan, I'm here to see--
Father-in-law.
Did you really think I was senile?
Stop pretending
to be a couple.
Father, I had no choice.
It was you who deceived me first.
I didn't mean to deceive you.
Master Yan, this is not Fu Zhi's fault.
It was I who said those words.
I'm to blame.
Forget it.
I've come around now.
I won't force you to marry.
You don't need to pretend anymore.
Fu Zhi, you are a lady after all,
and you can't risk your reputation.
You can handle things on your own,
but no matter how much you earn,
I still hope
you will have a good man to love you.
Master Yan,
Fu Zhi and I never pretend to love.
Fu Zhi and I love each other,
and I will be faithful to her.
I am very glad to hear that.
You are a guest,
so I'll prepare a big dinner to welcome you.
The military situation is urgent.
I'm here to seek help from Fu Zhi.
Just tell me what I can do for you.
Fu Zhi, this matter is of great importance.
Qingzhou urgently needs 30,000 dan of grain.
It must be delivered within seven days.
The court can allocate grain,
but we're pressed for time.
Although I have restaurants,
to gather 30,000 dan of grain
within seven days,
I'm afraid...
Father, I don't have many connections here.
Could you help us and act as a guarantor
to purchase private grain
from close merchants?
- Even at a high price--
- Master, you can't do that.
30,000 dan of grain will cost all our money.
Although you're from a noble family,
your annual salary is only 100 taels.
Before your betrothal gifts have arrived,
you expect us to financially help you?
Master Yan, if you're willing to help,
I can write a proof of debt right now,
and I'll definitely pay you back.
Master.
Officials are not trustworthy.
We used to lend money to people,
but they never paid back.
Did you take a liking to Fu Zhi,
or did you take a liking to our wealth?
You are obsessed with money yourself,
but not everyone is.
Master, I'm just thinking about our family.
After all, that's our hard-earned money.
How can we throw it around like this?
Mr. Shen, do you urgently need grain
because of Beijian?
Master Yan, to be honest,
the situation is still unclear.
Although war hasn't broken out yet,
we must not drop our guard.
Since you're personally seeking help,
it must be extremely urgent.
It is also a sign of trust in our family.
Though I'm just a merchant,
I know national security is above all.
Fu Zhi, here is my seal.
You have full authority
to dispatch grain from our granaries.
If it's not enough,
from today, all our shops
will only purchase grain and not sell goods.
We will also purchase private grain
from other major shops.
Thank you, Master Yan.
I will write the proof now.
Mr. Shen, are you treating me
like a profit-driven merchant?
Master, you don't think about yourself,
but think about Song.
If war really breaks out,
30,000 dan of grain won't be enough.
A proof will mean nothing then.
Merchants can only make money
in times of peace.
We can enjoy our wealth and safety
only when soldiers protect our country.
You short-sighted woman, stay out of this.
Master!
Help her back to her room.
Madam, get up.
Madam.
Thank you, Father.
I'd like to thank Fu Zhi and Master Yan
on behalf of our soldiers.
No need to thank me, both of you.
Come on, get up.
Fu Zhi.
I will arrange for the wagons
to transport grain right away.
I have other urgent things to do,
so I cannot stay with you.
Go ahead and do your things.
I will handle the grain matter properly.
Shen Zhi Shu!
Speak.
Shen Zhi Shu, listen carefully.
I am famously known in Shazhou
for loving handsome men.
If you come back with even one more scar,
I will dump you,
and then find ten men more handsome than you.
That won't do.
I have three scars here,
left from when my father disciplined me.
You must have a look
in case you dump me because of old scars.
- Here, look.
- Shen Zhi Shu!
Alright.
I was just kidding.
What I mean is,
I want you to come back safe and sound.
Not even a hair of your head will be harmed.
Do you hear me?
Wait for me.
I'll wait for you.
Your Majesty,
Beijian has submitted a diplomatic letter
for the third time
about the marriage alliance.
I've discussed with the court officials,
and we believe
Grand Tutor Shen's daughter, Shen Zhi Li,
is virtuous, talented, and dignified
and can serve as a model for all women.
I humbly request Your Majesty
to name her empress.
I second the proposal.
Your Majesty.
I previously thought
that marrying Beijian's goddess
could consolidate the border,
but seeing Lord Xu's fervent desire for war,
I thought twice
and realized that Lord Xu indeed made sense.
The Shen family holds a noble status.
They're known for their scholarly traditions,
unmatched in nobility.
Shen Zhi Li is indeed the perfect candidate
for empress.
I second the proposal.
You two are
actually sharing the same thought today.
Your Majesty,
previously,
Lord Gu and I indeed had disagreements,
but today, we happen to have the same view.
It precisely shows
Shen Zhi Li is the choice everyone expects.
Lord Xu is absolutely right.
I implore Your Majesty to have an empress
to stabilize the nation
and continue the royal lineage.
You are quite thoughtful.
But I've always respected the Shen family.
You're jointly recommending Shen Zhi Li
as empress.
Shouldn't you first ask Grand Tutor Shen
for his opinion?
I feared Your Majesty might have concerns,
so I've already requested Grand Tutor Shen
to co-sign the petition.
[Shen Wu Chen]
Your Majesty, the joint petition
has been presented before you.
I'll have the Ministry of Rites
prepare for the Announcement Ceremony,
and the Imperial Observatory
select an auspicious date for the wedding.
I request Your Majesty
to draft the decree soon
to announce the chosen empress to the world.
I second the proposal.
[Conferring Shen Zhi Li as Empress]
No matter what happened,
you were always on my side.
But now?
I do this to cut off Beijian's wild fancy
and your inappropriate feelings
for Meng Ting Hui.
Your Majesty,
you can hide it from anyone but me.
When you rewarded Meng Ting Hui in the past,
I did not say a word,
because I trusted your judgment
in appointing people.
However, Meng Ting Hui's identity
as the princess of Zhongwan
determines that she is not destined for you.
After much deliberation,
only in this way can Your Majesty
distance yourself from Meng Ting Hui.
But Meng Ting Hui knows nothing
about her origins.
Even if the remnants of Zhongwan
have designs on her,
I will personally resolve it
and absolutely not get her involved.
Why is her real identity such a big deal?
We're sure the remnants of Zhongwan plot
to restore their country.
If she one day learns of the past,
in the face of national hatred,
who can predict her choice?
For the stability of our country,
I dare not take any chances.
The late emperor gave me the Mandate Token,
granting me the power of life and death,
and bestowing supreme honor upon my family.
Today,
I'm going to use this token
to implore Your Majesty
to accept the recommendation
of the two chancellors and the ministers
- and establish Zhi Li as empress.
- Grand Tutor Shen!
You're forcing me too?
The ministers jointly recommended Zhi Li,
all with their own agendas.
But I make a promise here.
My family only prioritizes Your Majesty
and the Ning Empire,
and will absolutely not be swayed
by any faction.
After much deliberation,
I think
Zhi Li is the best candidate for empress.
To avoid any suspicion,
once the wedding ceremony concludes,
I'll move away from the capital with my wife,
retiring completely.
Your Majesty,
Director Meng requests an audience.
I implore Your Majesty to decide soon
to stabilize the overall situation.
[Conferring Shen Zhi Li as Empress]
Your Majesty,
Xu Ting, the Left Chancellor,
Gu Qin, the Right Chancellor,
along with the six ministries
and nine chief ministers,
a total of 236 court officials,
have jointly petitioned
to recommend Zhi Li as empress.
Grand Tutor Shen even
used the Mandate Token from the late emperor,
requesting Your Majesty
to hold the Announcement Ceremony
at the Sacred Ancestral Hall in seven days,
draft the empress appointment decree,
and announce it to the nation
for the national stability and people.
Fu Zhi,
when you returned from Shazhou last time,
you asked if I had feelings for His Majesty.
At that time, I was not sure
and hastily denied it.
But after several brushes with death,
His Majesty and I
have confessed our feelings to each other.
Because of ancestral rules,
we can't make our love public.
Yet we have burning love for each other.
But right now,
the entire court
jointly recommended Zhi Li as empress.
She is not only my colleague,
but also my close friend
who has faced life and death with me.
Facing the overt and covert attacks
in the court,
I have never been afraid.
But the current situation
has made me feel melancholy
for the first time.
I truly have no one else to confide in
about my complicated feelings but you.
I hope you can join hands with me
to recommend Shen Zhi Li as empress.
Everyone knows
Shen Zhi Li is your prized student.
Why should I help you consolidate your power?
Now, Meng Ting Hui's power is growing,
and her supporters are increasing day by day.
She is also on good terms
with the Shen family.
She
is the greatest threat to us.
If Grand Tutor Shen rallies the officials
to recommend Meng Ting Hui,
and then His Majesty says yes,
well,
neither of us can stop it.
If we recommend Shen Zhi Li as empress,
it can completely dash Meng Ting Hui's hopes
for becoming empress,
and also drive a wedge
between her and the Shen family.
The Censorate will inevitably be affected.
This is entirely beneficial to both of us.
Your concern is
that Shen Zhi Li is my student.
But Grand Tutor Shen
is the head of the Shen family,
and Shen Zhi Shu and Di Nian
are both His Majesty's confidants.
Which one
do you think I can easily manipulate?
The situation is now clear.
Either Meng Ting Hui
or Shen Zhi Li is to be the empress.
I believe
you have your own judgment
on the right choice.
Le Yan.
Zhi Li.
[Gu Mansion]
My name is indeed on the petition.
I have nothing to say.
We used to spend a happy time.
We honestly shared intimate words.
Is that all fake? Have you been pretending?
My feelings for you are absolutely true.
But Lord Xu and your father
jointly recommended you as empress.
It's already inevitable.
I had no choice but to make this decision.
All of you had no choice.
Even my open-minded parents have changed,
either avoiding me or remaining silent.
You all say you love me,
but in your eyes,
I am nothing but a puppet
you can manipulate at will.
So, in your hearts,
what I think
doesn't matter at all?
Le Yan,
I am full of regret.
How about I go to the palace immediately
and honestly confess to His Majesty?
Even if His Majesty is furious,
I will bear all the consequences alone.
No matter what happens,
I will not let you be implicated.
Master.
You are drunk.
Our love will never be accepted
by the public.
If it gets exposed,
not only you and I,
but even my parents and the entire Shen clan
would face controversy and condemnation.
Le Yan, if you want,
I will take you away right now.
I don't care about official career
or reputation.
I can give it all up.
Even if I am demoted to a commoner,
even if I live a simple, ordinary life,
as long as you are with me,
the wilderness will be paradise,
and a thatched hut will be our haven.
Le Yan,
trust me.
Zhi Li, you finally came.
I have something to tell you.
Recently, Yin Qing and I have been
investigating the person behind Ling Yun Fei.
- We didn't mean to hide it from you, but--
- Director Meng.
It doesn't matter anymore.
[Resignation]
I have already submitted this
to the Ministry of Personnel,
and this one is for you.
Starting today,
we can no longer work together
at the Censorate.
[Resignation]
You worked so hard to become a court official
and made great contributions here.
Are you really going to give up?
We are women, after all.
Meng,
I'm not afraid of losing this official job.
I'm only afraid of not being able to be
with the one I love.
I don't understand.
Why can't the world accept us?
You mean Lord Gu?
He and I are in love.
This is the first time I've loved someone.
No matter what it takes,
I don't want to give up.
I was just going to tell you
something about him.
Zhi Li.
Captain Di,
tell Zhi Li what you know.
He has been deceiving you all along.
People believe
Lady Yuan died protecting Lord Gu,
killed by bandits.
But she actually died
at the hands of Lord Gu.
Nian, you are talking nonsense.
I saw how sad he was
when he lost his wife and child.
Zhi Li,
he did it all to make you empress.
If you become empress,
only he will benefit from it.
Impossible.
He is absolutely not that kind of person.
Zhi Li,
Gu Qin is not worthy of you.
Zhi Li, we've been collecting evidence
of his crimes recently.
We're telling you in advance
because we don't want you
to hear it from someone else,
and even more,
we don't want to see you heartbroken.
I know it's hard for you to accept right now,
but this is the truth.
There is a person who can prove it.
Here is the military deployment map
you wanted.
Mr. Shangguan.
You're indeed well-informed.
You actually found out about my identity
in just a few days.
You used the Eternity Pill
to set up Ling Yun Fei.
How long do you think you can hide?
Who really caused his death, you or me?
Enough talking. Where is the thing I want?
[Ledger]
[Qingzhou Military Deployment Map]
It is time to show your true face.
Just as Your Majesty guessed,
they indeed
want the Qingzhou military deployment map.
[Shen Mansion]
The position of empress concerns the state.
With the two chancellors vying for power,
and Beijian coveting our country,
we need a suitable empress,
and you are the perfect person.
In seven days, you'll be made empress
at the Announcement Ceremony.
This is no longer a family matter,
but a state affair.
It is already a sure thing.
Father, it's strictly professional
between His Majesty and me.
I cannot be his empress.
And I'm already in love with someone else.
I'm sorry?
My teacher and I are in love with each other.
Do you want me to marry His Majesty
while I love someone else?
I cannot do it.
It's a crime of deceiving the emperor.
And for me, it's a heart-wrenching pain.
I dare you to say it again.
Father, even if I say it a million times,
I want to be with my teacher.
We truly love each other.
Our family has been upright for generations.
You read poetry and books
and learned etiquette,
not to use them to defy human ethics.
If your dear teacher truly liked you,
how could he
personally recommend you as empress?
He must have his reasons.
He promised
that even if he faces public criticism,
- he will still grow old with me.
- Wake up!
Master!
Zhi Li.
This is the first time
you have ever slapped me.